Oh yeah,
I also wanted to just talk about the VTT format really briefly.
If we view our source here,
we can see
Shrek.VTT.
No, we're looking at the binary of the web.
WebTT files always start with the capital letters web VTT.
And then they have a blank line and then they
have two pieces of time code separated by a dash,
dash,
greater than sign like a fancy arrow.
And then they have text and that text can have
a limited set of HTML in it.
It also has some reserved tags like the V tag,
which is for voice.
It actually lets you set a speaker name,
which you can decode in the browser
to do some interesting stuff with,
I suppose I've never really seen a lot of work done with that.
And you can see this is a really
long file.
There are some conventions that are used like using
a hyphen to signify that a speaker is changed.
And you can see that it's in
this case it's minutes,
seconds, and then dot milliseconds.
You can also add hours.
If we go further into the movies, scroll down.
It's hours,
minutes,
seconds,
and then milliseconds are always,
like milliseconds don't have a colon before them.
They have a period.
And then this pattern repeats until you get the end of the file.
There's nothing that signifies the end of the file.
You just have your last, your last caption.
And I've written these by hand.
It is not exactly fun.
There are online tools that will convert
from other subtitle formats like SRT,
Subrip.
You know,
there are some other things that you can do. There are earlier caption formats,
including ones that are used on DVDs that actually don't have text.
They look like text.
There are images of text where you have IDX files.
And you can use,
you know,
there are tools that can like OCR rip those.
It's
kind of goofy.
You can also download these.
If you upload a video to YouTube,
you can leave it as a private video.
So like people can't access it.
Sometimes it takes a few minutes or hours
depending on the length of the movie.
YouTube will generate subtitles and
VTT. And then you can download them.
And then you can delete the movie.
I worked on a project where we really needed to have good captions.
And we had no budget.
And even though we were self hosting the videos,
I ended up uploading them all to YouTube,
waiting for them to be captioned,
downloaded the captions,
deleted the files,
felt a lot.
It's a little bit dirty,
but
you know,
sometimes you do what you got to do for a project.
If you're not sure why your VTT file isn't working,
the W3C, not W3 schools, but the W3C,
like the consortium that
sets all these specifications,
has their own validator.
And before I paste Shrek in there,
I know the Shrek one works.
I want to look at their example code here.
Where we have this voice that's being set to Roger Bingham.
And that's again,
that's what the code looks like to actually signify who's speaking.
And you can also see to the right of the time code,
they're actually setting, I don't know, like
those of you who watch Netflix and
like some of these other streaming,
you know,
sometimes they'll put captions at the top or the left or the
right that signify like where the speaker is on the screen.
Right.
Here's how you can embed that kind of stuff in the VTT. But I'm not
sure that every browser has native support for actually space sheet,
like spatializing where the captions appear in a video tag.
They have different times here.
Metadata chapters,
they don't have example code for this,
because you can see like,
this regular VTT functions as metadata spec,
but not as chapter spec.
RTFS,
that probably stands for read the fucking specification.
And okay, okay, W3C, you are rude.
I'm going to paste Shrek in here now.
And it says,
this is boring,
your web VTT is valid.
It took 14 milliseconds.
So I'll put a link to this.
After the tutorial.
And then,
and then we've got this flex clip thing where.
I think this is the one I tried.
You can,
you don't have to log in.
Maybe you do to save.
I didn't get totally far with this.
But like you can,
you can drag your local media into here.
And it won't upload it to their site.
It will use it locally in your browser.
They're browser APIs for working with local files like that.
And then it gives you this interface.
Where you're typing the text,
you can set the speed of the video.
And it's kind of nice.
It's worth trying out.
There are a number of sites like this.
Amara,
which used to be called Universal subtitles,
was one.
Now they've kind of shifted to being like a
pay for service for like buying transcription.
And if you wanted to run your own,
yes,
I want to leave the page.
If you want to run your own HTML5 transcript editor.
Here's one that runs like locally using the same thing.
I believe like Node.js for those of you that are a
little bit more savvy about running server side stuff.
This might be something to check out.
But like this isn't a subtitling class.
So unless you're really,
really obsessed with VTT,
this should not be like the bulk of your projects.
I'm fine with,
you know,
if you're really interested in this.
Stay in the rabbit hole.
But I'm not sure if you're interested in this.
I'm mostly explaining this so that you understand how things work.